19th-20th Century Architecture Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
19th-20th Century Architecture Photograph Collection
1900-2005
VRC 35
Yale University Arts Library
24.16
58 boxes
Collection consists of mounted black and white and color reproductions of modern African, Australian, European, and Asian architecture. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of mounted black and white and color reproductions of modern African, Australian, European, and Asian architecture. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by country. Further sub-divided by city or other location, building type and name.
Architecture, Modern -- 19th century; Architecture, Modern -- 20th Century; Photographs; Reproductions
- Africa (Box 1)
  General
  [13 photographs]
  - Cape Town [2 photographs] (Box 1)
    [Folder with 1 loose photograph]
- Australia (Box 1)
  [4 photographs]
  [Folder with 18 loose photographs]
  - Adelaide [2 photographs] (Box 1)
  - Brisbane [4 photographs] (Box 1)
  - Melbourne [2 photographs] (Box 1)
  - Perth [2 photographs (Box 1)
  - Sydney [11 photographs] (Box 1)
    [Folder with 4 loose photographs]
    Xx Harbor Bridge, Sydney, see Large Size Architecture
  - Tasmania [5 photographs] (Box 1)
- Austria (Box 1)
  [6 photographs]
  - Vienna [33 photographs] (Box 2)
    [Folder with 14 loose photographs and 1 article]
    - Churches [7 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Government Buildings [11 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Houses [15 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Apartments [15 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Museums [3 photographs] (Box 3)
    - Secession Building [7 photographs] (Box 3)
- Bangladesh (Box 3)
  [2 photographs]
- Belgium (Box 3)
  [10 photographs]
  [Folder of 4 loose photographs]
  - Antwerp [4 photographs] (Box 3)
  - Brussels [16 photographs] (Box 3)
    - Houses [18 photographs] (Box 3)
      - Palais Stoclet [16 photographs] (Box 3)
      - Tassel House (12 Rue de Turin) [5 photographs] (Box 3)
- Britain (Box 4)
  [3 photographs]
  [Folder of 38 loose photographs and 4 articles]
  Xx Runconn: Plan, see: Medium Size
  - General Architects [17 photographs] (Box 4)
    [Folder with 1 article]
    Xx Charles Rennie McKintosh's Watercolors, see: Painting, Britain
  - Places A-M [101 photographs] (Box 4–5)
  - Places N-Z [59 photographs] (Box 5)
    X Windsor Castle, Exterior Views, see: Architecture, Gothic, Britain
  - Abbotsford [7 photographs] (Box 6)
    [Folder of 7 loose photographs]
    X Abbotsford Manor, Exterior Views, see: Large Size Architecture
  - Ascott [4 photographs] (Box 6)
  - Ashridge Park [8 photographs] (Box 6)
  - Balmoral Castle [3 photographs (Box 6)
    [Folder of 1 loose photograph]
  - Bexley Heath [7 photographs] (Box 6)
  - Birmingham [10 photographs] (Box 6)
    [Folder of 5 loose photographs]
  - Bradford [11 photographs] (Box 6)
  - Brighton [10 photographs] (Box 6)
  - Broadleys on Lake Windermere [5 photographs] (Box 6)
  - Cambridge [11 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Fitzwilliam Museum [3 photographs] (Box 7)
  - Cheadle [6 photographs] (Box 7)
  - Coventry [4 photographs] (Box 7)
  - Dublin [10 photographs] (Box 7)
    X Trinity College Museums (Dane & Woodward, Architects), see: Large Size Architecture
  - Eaton Hall [4 photographs] (Box 7)
  - Edinburgh [13 photographs] (Box 7)
    [Folder of 6 loose photographs]
  - Glasgow [12 photographs] (Box 7)
  - Godaming [5 photographs] (Box 7)
  - Halland [3 photographs] (Box 7)
  - Helensburgh [5 photographs] (Box 7)
  - Hertford [5 photographs] (Box 8)
  - Kilmalcolm [4 photographs] (Box 8)
  - Leeds [10 photographs] (Box 8)
    [Folder of 3 loose photographs]
  - Liverpool [8 photographs] (Box 8)
    [Folder of 8 loose photographs]
    - Cathedral [6 photographs] (Box 8)
      [Folder of 9 loose photographs]
    - Yorkshire House [1 photograph] (Box 8)
  - London [66 photographs] (Box 8–9)
    [Folder of 73 loose photographs and 6 articles]
    - Banks [3 photographs] (Box 9)
      - Bank of England [15 photographs (Box 9)
    - Churches [11 photographs] (Box 9)
      - Westminster Cathedral [3 photographs] (Box 9)
    - Expositions [16 photographs] (Box 10)
      - Crystal Palace [13 photographs] (Box 10)
    - Government Buildings [7 photographs] (Box 10)
      - Houses of Parliament [21 photographs] (Box 10)
      - Royal Courts of Justice [13 photographs] (Box 10)
      - Royal Mail House [15 photographs] (Box 11)
        X Royal Mail House, Interior, see: Medium Size Architecture
    - Houses [14 photographs] (Box 11)
      - Shaw House [3 photographs] (Box 11)
      - Swan House [6 photographs] (Box 11)
    - Houses-Apartments [5 photographs] (Box 11)
    - Monuments [4 photographs] (Box 11)
      - Albert Memorial [9 photographs] (Box 11)
    - Museums [1 photograph] (Box 11)
      - British Museums [6 photographs] (Box 11)
      - National Gallery [3 photographs] (Box 11)
    - Palaces [6 photographs] (Box 11)
    - Parks [2 photographs] (Box 11)
    - Squares [7 photographs] (Box 11)
    - Stations [9 photographs] (Box 12)
  - Manchester [40 photographs] (Box 12)
    - Persian Exposition (Box 12)
      Xx: Persian Exposition, see: Minor Arts
  - Marlow [7 photographs] (Box 12)
  - Mentmore [3 photographs] (Box 12)
  - Nottingham [3 photographs] (Box 12)
  - Oxford [9 photographs] (Box 12)
  - Rugby [3 photographs] (Box 13)
  - Scarisbrick [3 photographs] (Box 13)
  - Stratford-on-Avon [2 photographs] (Box 13)
    Xx Exterior, see Large Size
  - Warwick [2 photographs] (Box 13)
  - Whipsnade [6 photographs] (Box 13)
- China (Box 13)
  - Yenching University [1 photograph] (Box 13)
  - Union Medical College [3 photographs] (Box 13)
- Czechoslovakia (Box 13)
  [16 photographs]
- Denmark (Box 13)
  - Copenhagen [27 photographs] (Box 13)
    [Folder of 18 loose images]
- Egypt (Box 14)
  [7 photographs]
  [Folder of 10 loose photographs and 1 article]
  - Mosque of Mohamed Ali [5 photographs] (Box 14)
- Finland (Box 14)
  [21 photographs]
  [Folder of 17 loose photographs]
  - Helsinki [31 photographs] (Box 14)
  - Munkkiniemi [6 photographs] (Box 14)
  - Otaniemi [10 photographs] (Box 14)
  - Paimio [9 photographs] (Box 15)
  - Pori [15 photographs] (Box 15)
  - Sunila [9 photographs] (Box 15)
- France (Box 15)
  [Folder of 26 loose photographs and 5 articles]
  - Places A-G [23 photographs] (Box 16)
  - Places H-M [17 photographs] (Box 16)
  - Places N-Z [28 photographs] (Box 16)
  - General Architects [12 photographs] (Box 16)
    [Folder of 114 loose photographs]
    - Garnier, Tony [13 photographs] (Box 16)
    - Hector, Guimard [2 photographs] (Box 16)
    - Le Corbusier [10 photographs] (Box 17)
      [Folder with 3 loose photographs and 1 article]
    - Lequeu, Jean Jacques [6 photographs] (Box 17)
    - Viollet-le-Duc [5 photographs] (Box 17)
  - Assy [5 photographs] (Box 17)
  - Auteuil [5 photographs] (Box 17)
  - Auxerre [5 photographs] (Box 17)
  - Bordeaux [4 photographs] (Box 17)
  - Boulogne [3 photographs] (Box 17)
  - Bourges [2 photographs] (Box 17)
  - Chartes [2 photographs] (Box 17)
  - Chateau-Thierry [2 photographs] (Box 17)
  - Cherbourg [2 photographs] (Box 17)
  - Dinan la Rance [2 photographs] (Box 17)
  - Dol [2 photographs] (Box 17)
  - Drancy [3 photographs] (Box 17)
  - Dreux [8 photographs] (Box 17)
  - Eveux [14 photographs] (Box 18)
  - Evreux [2 photographs] (Box 18)
  - Garches [7 photographs] (Box 18)
  - Hauterive [10 photographs] (Box 18)
  - Le Havre [3 photographs] (Box 18)
  - Le Raincy [9 photographs] (Box 18)
  - Lille [9 photographs] (Box 18)
  - Lyon [19 photographs] (Box 18)
  - Marseilles [16 photographs] (Box 19)
  - Montmagny [3 photographs] (Box 19)
  - Morey St. Denis [2 photographs] (Box 19)
  - Nancy [5 photographs] (Box 19)
  - Neuilly [4 photographs] (Box 19)
  - Nice [6 photographs] (Box 19)
  - Paris [18 photographs] (Box 19)
    [Folder with 58 loose photographs]
    [Folder with 7 loose photographs]
    - Air Views [11 photographs] (Box 20)
    - Arches [1 photograph] (Box 20)
      - Arc du Carrousel [6 photographs] (Box 20)
      - Arc de Triomphe [8 photographs] (Box 20)
    - Banks [6 photographs] (Box 20)
    - Bridges (Box 20)
      - Pont Alexandre III [8 photographs] (Box 20)
      - Pont Bir-Hakeim [5 photographs] (Box 20)
    - Churches [7 photographs] (Box 20)
      - Chapelle Expiatore [7 photographs] (Box 20)
      - La Madeleine [12 photographs] (Box 20)
        Xx La Madeleine, Sculpture of High Altar, see Marochetti, Carlo under Sculpture, France
      - La Trinite [3 photographs] (Box 20)
      - Notre Dame de Lorette [4 photographs] (Box 20)
      - Notre Dame du Travail [6 photographs] (Box 20)
      - Church of Rambouillet [8 photographs] (Box 21)
      - Sacre Coeur [4 photographs] (Box 21)
      - S. Eugene [7 photographs] (Box 21)
      - S. Vincent de Paul [5 photographs] (Box 21)
    - Expositions (Box 21)
      - Exposition of 1878 [7 photographs] (Box 21)
      - Exposition of 1889 [13 photographs] (Box 21)
        [Folder of 7 loose images]
        - Eiffel Tower [16 photographs] (Box 21)
      - Exposition Universelle 1900 [14 photographs] (Box 21)
        [Folder of 1 loose image]
      - Arts Decoratifs 1925 [39 photographs] (Box 22)
        Xx Color detail of Pavillion d'un Collectionneur, see Dupas under Painting, France
      - Exposition of 1929 [5 photographs] (Box 22)
      - Colonial Exposition of 1931 [9 photographs] (Box 22)
      - International Exposition of 1937 [19 photographs] (Box 22)
    - Fountains [19 photographs] (Box 23)
    - Garages [2 photographs] (Box 23)
    - Government Buildings [13 photographs] (Box 23)
      - Chambre des Deputes [5 photographs] (Box 23)
      - Palais de Justice [29 photographs] (Box 23)
      - Tribunal de Commerce [10 photographs] (Box 23)
    - Hospitals [7 photographs] (Box 23)
    - Houses [23 photographs] (Box 24)
      [Folder with 2 photographs and 1 article]
      - Hotel de Beauharnais [5 photographs] (Box 24)
      - Louis Carre House [5 photographs] (Box 24)
      - Hotel Pourtales [5 photographs] (Box 24)
    - Houses-Apartments [12 photographs] (Box 24)
    - Libraries (Box 24)
      - Bibliotheque Nationale [22 photographs] (Box 24)
      - Bibliotheque S.Genevieve [32 photographs] (Box 24)
    - Monuments [3 photographs] (Box 25)
      Xx Tomb of Napolean, see Architecture, Renaissance, France, Paris, Hotels, and Hotel des Invalides
    - Museums [14 photographs] (Box 25)
      - Louvre [19 photographs] (Box 25)
    - Palaces [2 photographs] (Box 25)
      Xx 19th Century Additions to the Palais Royal, see Architecture, Renaissance, France, Paris, Palaces, Palais Royal
    - Parks [8 photographs] (Box 25)
      Xx Jardin des Plantes, Aerial View, see Medium Size
    - Schools [22 photographs] (Box 25)
    - Squares [7 photographs] (Box 25)
      - Place de la Concord [5 photographs] (Box 25)
    - Stations (Box 25)
      - Gare de l'Est [5 photographs] (Box 25)
      - Gare Montparnasse [3 photographs] (Box 25)
      - Gare du Nord [4 photographs] (Box 25)
      - Gare du Quai-d'Orsay [4 photographs] (Box 26)
      - Metro Entrance [8 photographs] (Box 26)
    - Stores [7 photographs] (Box 26)
      - Central Market [14 photographs] Streets [ (Box 26)
    - Theatres [9 photographs] (Box 26)
      - Opera House [18 photographs] (Box 26)
      - Theatre des Champs Elysees [7 photographs] (Box 26)
  - Poissy-Sur-Seine [9 photographs] (Box 26)
  - Ronchamp [13 photographs] (Box 27)
  - Royan [2 photographs] (Box 27)
  - Saint Brieu [2 photographs] (Box 27)
  - Saintes [2 photographs] (Box 27)
  - Strasbourg [5 photographs] (Box 27)
  - Thiepval [2 photographs] (Box 27)
  - Tours [22 photographs] (Box 27)
  - Vence [2 photographs] (Box 27)
  - Verdun [2 photographs] (Box 27)
  - Versailles [1 photograph] (Box 27)
  - Villejuif [3 photographs] (Box 27)
  - Vincennes (Box 27)
    - Eglise St. Louis [1 photograph] (Box 27)
- Germany (Box 28)
  [9 photographs]
  [Folder with 20 loose photographs and 3 articles]
  [Folder with 32 loose photographs and 1 article]
  Innen-Dekoration: Die Gesamte Wohnungskunst in Bild und Wort-Herausegeber (2/1929)
  - General Architects [24 photographs] (Box 28)
    [Folder with 4 loose photographs and 2 articles]
  - Places A-G [24 photographs] (Box 28)
  - Places H-M [9 photographs] (Box 28)
  - Places N-Z [12 photographs] (Box 28)
  - Alfred a.d. Leine [7 photographs] (Box 29)
    [Folder with 3 loose photographs]
  - Bayreuth [3 photographs] (Box 29)
  - Berlin [28 photographs] (Box 29)
    [Folder with 40 loose photographs and 3 articles]
    - Churches [13 photographs] (Box 29)
    - Government Buildings [9 photographs] (Box 29)
      - Neue Wache [4 photographs] (Box 29)
    - Houses [8 photographs] (Box 29)
    - Housing [23 photographs] (Box 30)
    - Industrial Buildings [5 photographs] (Box 30)
      - A.E.G. Turbine [5 photographs] (Box 30)
    - Museums [22 photographs] (Box 30)
    - Palaces [6 photographs] (Box 30)
    - Stores [7 photographs] (Box 30)
    - Theatres [7 photographs] (Box 30)
  - Bingen [2 photographs] (Box 30)
  - Bonn [4 photographs] (Box 30)
  - Brandenburg [2 photographs] (Box 30)
  - Bremen [2 photographs] (Box 30)
  - Chemnitz [3 photographs] (Box 31)
  - Coblenz [3 photographs] (Box 31)
  - Cologne [11 photographs] (Box 31)
    [Folder with 6 loose photographs]
    - Expositions [12 photographs] (Box 31)
  - Darmstadt [14 photographs] (Box 31)
  - Delstern [2 photographs] (Box 31)
  - Dessau [10 photographs] (Box 31)
  - Dresden [16 photographs] (Box 31)
  - Dusseldorf [10 photographs] (Box 32)
  - Essen [13 photographs] (Box 32)
  - Frankfurt [15 photographs] (Box 32)
    [Folder with 9 loose photographs]
    - Great Market [4 photographs] (Box 32)
    - Churches [9 photographs] (Box 32)
    - Houses [5 photographs] (Box 32)
    - Housing [21 photographs] (Box 32)
    - Industrial Buildings [1 photograph] (Box 33)
      - I.G. Farben Factory [8 photographs] (Box 33)
        Xx Exterior, see Medium Size, Architecture, Modern, Germany
      - Gas Works [2 photographs] (Box 33)
  - Fussen [4 photographs] (Box 33)
  - Guben [2 photographs] (Box 33)
  - Hamburg [14 photographs] (Box 33)
    [Folder with 13 loose photographs]
    - The Sprinkenhof [6 photographs] (Box 33)
  - Hanover [5 photographs] (Box 33)
  - Heidelberg [5 photographs] (Box 33)
  - Herren-Chiemsee [9 photographs] (Box 33)
  - Hindenburg [4 photographs] (Box 34)
  - Hochst-Am-Main [6 photographs] (Box 34)
  - Jena [2 photographs] (Box 34)
  - Karlsruhe [4 photographs] (Box 34)
  - Kehlheim [2 photographs] (Box 34)
  - Kiel [3 photographs] (Box 34)
  - Konigsberg [2 photographs] (Box 34)
  - Kaefeld [4 photographs] (Box 34)
  - Leipzig [9 photographs] (Box 34)
    [Folder with 5 loose photographs]
    Xx Battle of the Nations Memorial, see Medium Size, Architecture, Modern, Germany
  - Linderhof [12 photographs] (Box 34)
  - Luckenwalde [2 photographs] (Box 34)
  - Mulheim a.d. Ruhr [3 photographs] (Box 34)
  - Munich [24 photographs] (Box 35)
    [Folder with loose 10 photographs]
    - Propylaea [6 photographs] (Box 35)
    - Tomb of Unknown Soldier [5 photographs] (Box 35)
    - Churches [6 photographs] (Box 35)
      - Basilica of St. Boniface [3 photographs] (Box 35)
    - Museums [6 photographs] (Box 35)
      - Glyptothek [7 photographs] (Box 35)
  - Neuschwanstein [13 photographs] (Box 35)
  - Nurnberg [2 photographs] (Box 36)
  - Oberhausen [1 photograph] (Box 36)
  - Potsdam [15 photographs] (Box 36)
    - Einstein Observatory [10 photographs] (Box 36)
    - Palaces [11 photographs] (Box 36)
  - Regensburg [2 photographs] (Box 36)
  - Stolzenfels [1 photograph] (Box 36)
  - Strassbourg [3 photographs] (Box 36)
  - Stuttgart [20 photographs] (Box 36)
    [Folder with 8 loose photographs and 2 articles]
  - Tannenburg [3 photographs] (Box 36)
  - Weimar [6 photographs] (Box 37)
  - Wiesbaden [10 photographs] (Box 37)
- Greece (Box 37)
  [Folder with 7 loose photographs and 1 article]
- Holland (Box 37)
  [38 photographs]
  [Folder with 31 loose photographs and 1 article]
  - General Architecture [4 photographs] (Box 38)
  - Amsterdam [25 photographs] (Box 38)
    - Banks [8 photographs] (Box 38)
    - Housing [6 photographs] (Box 38)
    - Municipal Housing [6 photographs] (Box 38)
    - Private Enterprise Housing [5 photographs] (Box 38)
    - Public Utilities Housing [27 photographs] (Box 38)
  - Hilversum [39 photographs] (Box 39)
    Xx Hotel Gooilands, Plan, see Medium Size
  - Rotterdam [16 photographs] (Box 39)
    Xx Museum Boymaus, Plan, see Medium Size
  - Utrecht [7 photographs] (Box 39)
- Hong Kong (Box 40)
- Hungary (Box 40)
  [19 photographs]
  [Folder with 1 travel brochure]
- India (Box 40)
  [12 photographs]
  - Chandigarh [7 photographs] (Box 40)
  - New Delhi [7 photographs] (Box 40)
  - Hyderabad [4 photographs] (Box 40)
- Israel (Box 40)
- Italy (Box 41)
  [Folder with 9 loose photographs and 1 article]
  - General Architects [13 photographs] (Box 41)
  - Places A-G [31 photographs] (Box 41)
  - Places H-M [5 photographs] (Box 41)
  - Places N-Z [27 photographs] (Box 41)
  - Bologna [4 photographs] (Box 42)
  - Florence [37 photographs] (Box 42)
    [Folder with 2 loose photographs]
    Xx Tribuna del Galileo, see Medium Size
  - Genoa [15 photographs] (Box 42)
    - Camposanto [7 photographs] (Box 42)
      Xx Photographs of Individual Funerary Monuments, see Sculpture, Italy, 18th-20th centuries
  - Lake Como [2 photographs] (Box 42)
  - Littoria [5 photographs] (Box 42)
  - Milan [10 photographs] (Box 43)
    [Folder with 4 loose images and 2 articles]
    Xx Galleria Vittorio Emanuele, Exterior and Interior, see Medium Size
    - Arches [3 photographs] (Box 43)
    - Churches [2 photographs] (Box 43)
    - Gates [3 photographs] (Box 43)
    - Office Buildings [8 photographs] (Box 43)
    - Palaces [5 photographs] (Box 43)
    - Stores [7 photographs] (Box 43)
  - Montecassino [5 photographs] (Box 43)
  - Naples [24 photographs] (Box 43–44)
  - Padua [1 photograph] (Box 44)
  - Palermo [16 photographs] (Box 44)
  - Rome (Box 44)
    [Folder with 10 loose photographs and 1 article]
    - General [10 photographs] (Box 44)
    - General Views [11 photographs] (Box 44)
      - Forum of Mussolini [2 photographs] (Box 44)
    - Churches [9 photographs] (Box 44)
      - S. Paolo F.L.M. [8 photographs] (Box 44)
        Xx S. Paolo F.L.M., Plan, see Small Size, Architecture, Early Christian, Italy
        Xx S. Paolo F.L.M., Interiors, see Small size, Architecture, Early Christian, Italy
    - Expositions [10 photographs] (Box 44)
    - Government Buildings [12 photographs] (Box 45)
    - Monuments [5 photographs] (Box 45)
    - Museums [4 photographs] (Box 45)
      Xx Vatican Museum, Interior, see Architecture, Renaissance, Italy, Rome, Vatican, Museum
    - Palaces [9 photographs] (Box 45)
    - Schools [4 photographs] (Box 45)
    - Squares [2 photographs] (Box 45)
    - Stadiums [6 photographs] (Box 45)
  - Sabaudia [3 photographs] (Box 45)
  - San Remo [8 photographs] (Box 45)
  - San Remo [8 photographs] (Box 45)
  - Turin [19 photographs] (Box 45)
    Xx International Exposition (including Forecourt by P. Behrens, see Medium Size
    - Expositions [14 photographs] (Box 46)
    - Industrial Buildings [3 photographs] (Box 46)
  - Venice [10 photographs] (Box 46)
    [Folder with 2 loose photograph
  - Verona [4 photographs] (Box 46)
  - Vincigliata [20 photographs] (Box 46)
- Japan (Box 47)
  [22 photographs]
  [Folder with 6 loose photographs and 1 article]
  - Tokyo [20 photographs] (Box 47)
- Lebanon (Box 47)
  [1 photograph]
- Monaco (Box 47)
  - Monte Carlo [5 photographs] (Box 47)
    - Casino [16 photographs] (Box 47)
    - Theatre [5 photographs] (Box 47)
- New Zealand (Box 47)
- Norway (Box 47)
- Palestine (Box 47)
  - Jerusalem [3 photographs] (Box 47)
- Poland (Box 47)
- Portugal (Box 47)
  [11 photographs]
- Russia (Box 48)
  [Folder with 4 loose photographs and 3 articles]
  - Batumi [1 photograph] (Box 48)
  - Kherkov [1 photograph] (Box 48)
  - Kiev [3 photographs] (Box 48)
  - Leningrad [31 photographs] (Box 48)
  - Moscow [28 photographs] (Box 48)
    [Folder with 2 photographs]
    - Tomb of Lenin [2 photographs] (Box 49)
      Xx Tomb of Lenin, see Medium Size, Architecture, Modern, Russia
  - Rostov-on-Dor [1 photograph] (Box 49)
  - Sochi [1 photograph] (Box 49)
  - Taschkent [1 photograph] (Box 49)
  - Tbilisi [1 photograph] (Box 49)
- South Africa (Box 49)
- Spain (Box 49)
  [25 photographs]
  - Barcelona (Box 49)
    - Churches [15 photographs] (Box 49)
    - Expositions [6 photographs] (Box 49)
    - Houses [2 photographs] (Box 49)
      - Casa Batllo [7 photographs] (Box 49)
      - Casa Quell [7 photographs] (Box 49)
      - Casa Mila [39 photographs] (Box 50)
    - Parks [11 photographs] (Box 50)
  - Madrid [10 photographs] (Box 50)
- Sweden (Box 51)
  [8 photographs]
  [Folder with 36 photographs]
  - Stockholm [24 photographs] (Box 51)
    - Children's Home [3 photographs] (Box 51)
    - Cinema [4 photographs] (Box 51)
    - Housing [11 photographs] (Box 51)
    - Restaurants [4 photographs] (Box 51)
    - Schools [5 photographs] (Box 51)
    - Town Hall [6 photographs] (Box 51)
- Switzerland (Box 52)
  [17 photographs]
  [Folder with 32 loose photographs]
  - Agra-Lugano [4 photographs] (Box 52)
  - Basel [30 photographs] (Box 52)
    Xx Hoffman LaRoche Building, St. Antonius Church, see Large Size
  - Dornach [3 photographs] (Box 52)
  - Geneva [5 photographs] (Box 52)
  - Grindelwald Valley [1 photograph] (Box 52)
  - Interlaken (Box 52)
  - Lucerne [11 photographs] (Box 52)
    Xx Museum and Auditorium, see Large Size
    - Water Tower and Bridge [4 photographs] (Box 52)
      [1 loose photograph]
  - Luggno [2 photographs] (Box 53)
  - Mammern [2 photographs] (Box 53)
  - Montana [7 photographs] (Box 53)
  - Pilatus [1 photograph] (Box 53)
  - Ruschlikon [2 photographs] (Box 53)
  - Saint Gall (Box 53)
  - Vevey [5 photographs] (Box 53)
    Xx Market Hall and Auditorium, see Large Size
    Xx Bridges by Maillart, see Large Size
  - Zollikon [11 photographs] (Box 53)
  - Zurich [38 photographs] (Box 53)
    Xx Workbundsiedlung "Neubuhl", see Large Size
- Thailand (Box 54)
- Turkey (Box 54)
  - Angora (Box 54)
    Xx New Palace, Exterior and Interior, see Large Size
- Yugoslavia (Box 54)
- Latin America (Box 54)
  - General (Box 54)
    [Folder with 2 articles]
  - Argentina (Box 54)
    - Buenos Aires [26 photographs] (Box 54)
  - Bolivia (Box 54)
  - Brazil (Box 54)
    [Folder with 28 loose photographs and 3 articles]
    - Belem [1 photograph] (Box 54)
    - Belo Horizonte [6 photographs] (Box 54)
      - Casino [6 photographs] (Box 54)
    - Niteroi [2 photographs] (Box 55)
      - Elementary School [2 photographs] (Box 55)
      - Vital Brazil Institute [2 photographs] (Box 55)
    - Olinda [1 photograph] (Box 55)
    - Ouro Preto [3 photographs] (Box 55)
    - Recife [9 photographs] (Box 55)
    - Rio de Janeiro [6 photographs] (Box 55)
      - Apartments [4 photographs] (Box 55)
      - Boat Station [3 photographs] (Box 55)
      - Brazilian Press Association [7 photographs] (Box 55)
      - Cavalcanti House [2 photographs] (Box 55)
      - Day Nursery [4 photographs] (Box 55)
      - Industrial School [4 photographs] (Box 55)
      - Itamarati Palace [2 photographs] (Box 55)
      - Ministry of Education [7 photographs] (Box 55)
      - Niemeyer House [2 photographs] (Box 55)
      - Providence Building [1 photograph] (Box 56)
      - Realengo Housing [3 photographs] (Box 56)